SMITHA RAO ALURI

designer | illustrator | creative thinker

+1 646-852-8648 smitharaoaluri@newschool.edu www.smitha-aluri.com

I am a visual designer and illustrator from India, currently pursuing an MFA in Design & Technology at Parsons School of Design. Research, curiosity and the constant need to experiment with new media and material, fuel my drive to keep learning.

EDUCATION

MFA Design and Technology 2021–2023

PARSONS SCHOOL OF DESIGN, New York City (The New School)

Bachelor of Visual Arts (BVA) 2015 - 2019

STELLA MARIS COLLEGE, Chennai (Affiliated to the University of Madras) CGPA – 8.4 | 1st Rank

Indian School Certificate (ISC) 2014 SISHYA, Chennai 97.5%

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- > Certified IBM Quantum Practioner, IBM Skills Academy (2021)
- > Finalist and Honorable Mention under the Creative Use of Quantum Technology in Visual Arts at IBM's Quantum Design Jam along with The New School (2021)
- > Participated in a group project to create 'Interaction at a Distance' along with other students from Parsons School of Design and Tsinghua University (Beijing) (2021)
- > Won 'Popular Choice' for TalentHouse contest 'Create artwork for Niall Horan's album, Heartbreak Weather' (2020)
- > Graduated as best outgoing student and 1st rank holder (BVA) from the Department of Fine Arts, Stella Maris College (2019)
- > Proficiency Prize for four consecutive years for the BVA program, Stella Maris College (2016 2019)
- > Presented the following papers at 'Student Speak', Student Seminar, Stella Maris College:
- · Kunstwollen Tracing the link between German and Art (2017)
- Behind the Scenes, Beyond the Screens The art department in film and television (2018)
- Explore, Experiment, Experience An overview of my practice (2019)
- > Completed a Certificate Course in Advanced Digital Illustration (Aug – Sep 2018)
- > Dr. Sr. Angel Mary FMM Award for highest mark in Art in Europe (2017–2018)
- > Completed A1 and A2 levels in German, InaWord Institute (2016 2017)
- > Ranked in the top 1% in India in the science stream (ISC 2014)

EXPERIENCE

Visualiser

RUBECON COMMUNICATIONS,

May 2019 - June 2020, Chennai

- » worked on branding, identity, logo design, packaging, editorial and print design, advertising campaigns, web design, content for social media and digital platforms, visual merchandising
- > worked on a range of projects for clients in the FMCG, real estate, education, retail, media, manufacturing and industrial sectors

Creative Intern

RUBECON COMMUNICATIONS

April 2018 - April 2019, Chennai

Intern

GALLERY VEDA

Dec 2017, Chennai

- » worked on the catalogue (research & writing) for Vardah, an auction of Modern & Contemporary Indian Art organised with Christie's, in aid of the Rotary Club of Madras
- > in-charge of registration and providing the guests an overview of the listed pieces and participating artists on the Preview and Auction Nights

Intern

BY HAND FROM THE HEART: MAKERS MARKET Oct 2016, Chennai

> in-charge of registration and display, co-ordinated with the participants, venue staff, guests and press for smooth functioning of the event

Freelancing

illustration, video editing, designed logo & stationary, menu, invitations, greeting cards & other collaterals for multiple organisations, college clubs, unions and events

SKILLS

Software & Code

Adobe XD, Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop, Indesign, Premiere Pro, After Effects, iMovies, Procreate, Keynote, Pages, Invision, Microsoft Office, Google Suite, JS, HTML, CSS

Creative

Branding and identity, packaging design, print & publication design, art direction, sketching & storyboarding, design research & thinking, photography, 2D animation, illustration, paper mechanics, prototyping, video editing

Languages

English (Fluent) Tamil (Conversational)
Hindi (Fluent) German (Beginner)

Telugu (Conversational)